BHARATH RAIGARI

SKILLS

Programming Skills

Python · JavaScript · NodeJS · Bash ·

GROOVY · Rest API · YAML

Databases and Servers

 $MySQL \cdot PostgreSQL \cdot MongoDB \cdot NGINX \cdot$

Apache · LAMP Stack

DevOps Tools

Jenkins · Docker · ELK · Vagrant · Ansible ·

Kubernetes \cdot Helm \cdot Prometheus \cdot IaC \cdot

Terraform · GIT · SSO

Systems Administration

Linux · RHEL · Firewall · TCP/IP · Logs ·

Troubleshooting · Shell Script · SSL/TLS

AWS Cloud

IAM · VPC · EC2 · S3 · EKS · Route 53 ·

ELB · Security Groups · RDS · Lambda ·

ECS · API Gateway · Cloud Formation

EDUCATION

Masters Networking and Systems Administration

Rochester Institue of Technology

2018 - 2021

Rochester, NY

B.Tech Electronics and Communication Eng.

Amrita University

2012 - 2016

Kollam, KL

ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduate Merit Scholarship

Awarded with 100% tuition waiver and a Graduate Assistantship by Dept. NSSA at RIT

Grad. Student Ambassador

Selected as an ambassador for proven academic excellence and interpersonal skills at RIT

This is a second of the second

Recognition from Infosys for dedication to developing use cases and POCs for the client

DevOps Engineer

SUMMARY

IT Professional with over 5 years of experience in managing application infrastructure in various business sectors. Knowledge in enabling the DevOps practices within the existing application development workflow. Proficient in implementing CI/CD pipeline and the enabling tools, automating the configuration and deployment of microservices, integrating security and monitoring for modern applications using Agile methodology.

EXPERIENCE

Analytics Solutions Engineer

2022 - 2023

LSEG

Buffalo, NY

London Stock Exchange Group is a global company that offers technology for providing financial data and analytics to numerous clients. My role was to maintain infra and enable deployment of containerized workloads on AWS using DevOps tools.

- Build and deploy CI/CD pipeline across development and production environments using Jenkins, GitHub, Docker and Kubernetes; automated build and deploy to AWS
- Co-ordinated in migrating two applications from on-premise to AWS Cloud, reducing server compute costs by 30% and improved analytics performance by using AWS ETL
- Worked with AWS services like EC2, S3, Lambda, IAM, Route 53, VPC, ELB, RDC
- Developed and improved Terraform scripts to automate the infrastructure provision on AWS for multiple environments reducing time to provision from days to hours
- Developed and maintained a containerized environment by coding custom docker compose files to deploy on Amazon ECS; enabling 10 times faster app release cycle
- Migrated MySQL DB to Amazon Aurora for 10x reduced cost and 99.99% availability
- Deployed authorization and notification microservices to AWS EKS using Helm chart.
 Configured ELK stack to monitor the microservices deployed on Kubernetes cluster

Infrastructure Admin

2020 - 2022

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

RIT is the university where I did my masters. I have joined the systems administration team to maintain, troubleshoot and automate the provision of infrastructure on campus.

- Automated the configuration management of Linux servers across 42 labs at RIT using Ansible, eliminating 40% of the manual work; worked on RHEL system roles
- Improved Linux server security by enabling logging, and configuring the parameters like firewall, file system, kernel, sshd, and sudoers by using specific Ansible modules
- Provided resolution to 50+ daily tickets that included troubleshooting authentication, performance, and network issues to ensure 8000 systems were fully operational
- Experience with tools like Nagios, Datadog for monitoring servers and applications
- Developed and enhanced 20+ scripts in Python and Bash to automate Linux Server Administration for systems monitoring, process management, setting up CRON jobs
- Configured Apache NGINX servers for better performance and enhanced security.
 Expertise in DNS, DHCP, network monitoring, load balancers, firewalls, reverse proxy
- Lead and trained a small team of 3 interns to get familiar with the existing IT tools and implemented the infrastructure for the day-to-day operations of the labs at RIT

Systems Engineer

2016 - 2018

Infosys

Trivandrum, KL

Infosys is a multi-national company that offers IT services to various clients around the world. I have contributed to the development and testing of REST APIs to integrate with a dashboard app utilizing the Predix Cloud platform.

- Co-ordinated with a team of 8 to identify the client requirements and design REST APIs using Python Django framework. Tested 1000s of API requests using Postman
- Implemented authentication to the web app and secure API endpoints using Auth0
- Configured the tools for development and ensure security of the environment;
 Documented the design patterns, features, configuration and troubleshooting
- Created proof of concepts according to the client's requirements; performed coding, testing and debugging of code helping reduce the operational costs by 40%
- Provided on-call support to the clients for troubleshooting application access issues.
 Participated in regular stand-up meetings to discuss and update the project status